# SABEER CA

### Web Developer

Interested in working as a developer for leading software company and serve its clients by providing excellent software experience and technical support.

★ sabeerzabi@gmail.com



+91 9633743391



sabeerzabi.github.io



18 October, 1996

Web Developer with 5 years of experience in developing user interfaces, testing, and debugging. Proven ability in optimizing web functionality that improves data retrieval and workflow efficiencies. 14 application websites and 14 CMS websites have developed.

### **EDUCATION**

### **Bsc. Computer Science**

University of Calicut, College of applied science Ayalur, Palakkad

2017

Overall scored percentage 75%

### **Plus Two Computer Science**

GBHSS Nemmara, Palakkad

Overall scored percentage 70%

#### **SSLC**

2014

SMHSS Ayalur, Palakkad

2012

Overall scored percentage 90%

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Senior Software Engineer**

Litebreeze Infotech

02/2021 - Present

1.5 years experience - Laravel, Python

SmartCity Kochi

### **Software Engineer**

2base technologies

08/2018 - 02/2021

2.5 years experience - Laravel, Scrapy

Palakkad

### Web Developer

Fortius Technologies

07/2017 - 08/2018

1.1 year experience - Codeigniter, Wordpress

Ayyathol, Thrissur

## LATEST PROJECTS

#### Blinkvisa

 Blinkvisa is a Laravel application for booking visas, flights, hotels, and activities. I am the project lead and one of the developers in this project. Here 3 different APIs used for getting data of hotels, flights, and activities and 2 payment gateways Integrations. We have done the integration of sending messages via Email, Sms, and Whatsapp.

### Flowbot Bar

• Flowbot bar is an IoT application for pouring beer using a device. I am the project lead and one of the developers of this project. I handled the backend of this project, it's done by Laravel. The frontend device section is integrated with Django. Some Sensors are used in this project for getting data like Temperature sensors, Pressure Sensors, Flow sensors, etc...

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### **PHP**

Laravel, Codeigniter, Wordpress, Slim

#### **Javascript**

Jquery, Twig Js, Require Js, Vue Js

#### **Python**

Scrapy

#### **Database**

MySQL, Elasticsearch, Redis

#### **Others**

Google Data Studio, Git, Chrome Plugin, Linux

#### **Basic Knowledge**

React, Django, Node, HTML and CSS, C, C++, Java, VB.net, Android

### PERSONAL INFORMATION

**Email**: sabeerzabi@gmail.com

Phone: +91 9633743391

**Address:** Chirapurath (ho), Chakrai, Thiruvazhiyad (Po), Palakkad, 678510, Kerala, India

### **LANGUAGES**

#### Malayalam

*Native or Bilingual Proficiency* 

### English

*Professional Working Proficiency* 

**Elementary Proficiency** 

#### Tamil

Full Professional Proficiency

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Hall Of Fame (2020)

2base technologies